A film about The Doors
When You're Strange is a documentary, music film directed by Tom DiCillo.
The creative chemistry of four brilliant artists —drummer John Densmore, guitarist Robby Kreiger, keyboardist Ray
Manzarek and singer Jim Morrison— made The Doors one of America's most iconic and influential rock bands.
Using footage shot between their formation in 1965 and Morrison's death in 1971, it follows the band from the
corridors of UCLA's film school, where Manzarek and Morrison met, to the stages of sold-out arenas.
Narrator (voice), played by Johnny Depp.
Self (archive footage), played by Jim Morrison.
Self (archive footage), played by John Densmore.
Self (archive footage), played by Ray Manzarek.
Self (archive footage), played by Robby Krieger.
Self (voice), played by Jim Ladd.
When You're Strange is a 2009 music documentary film
about the American rock band the Doors.
It was written and directed by Tom DiCillo and narrated by Johnny Depp.
The film covers the band's formation in 1965, its development over the next two years, the release of its debut album and subsequent
albums, and vocalist Jim Morrison's extensive use of alcohol and drugs, which led to his death in Paris in July 1971.
The film features archival footage of rehearsals, TV broadcasts and concert performances, private
cine-film and the background to Morrison's arrest at a 1969 Miami concert and later trial.
It also includes the first public release of material from
Morrison's 1969 featurette HWY: An American Pastoral.
The Doors' keyboardist Ray Manzarek, who was not pleased with the 1991 biopic The Doors, stated
prior to the film's release that "This will be the true story of the Doors ...
the anti-Oliver Stone."
The film explores themes of california, poet, trial, rock band, dying young.